You are building an Awwwards Mobile App of the Year winner. This is "LifeQuran", a premium Spiritual Productivity Ecosystem for high-performing professionals. Every single detail matters. No shortcuts. No generic solutions.

<company>
Name: LifeQuran
Tagline: "Elevating Devotion through Divine Design"
Focus: A gamified, high-end Al-Qur'an experience for busy professionals.
Signature: Dedicated to the Global Muslim Ummah 🤲
Stats:
- 100% Immersive Reading Environment
- 5-Minute Daily "Istiqomah" Tracks
- 60FPS Fluid Motion Architecture
</company>

<design_philosophy>
"Divine Nature Architecture." The UI must feel like a digital sanctuary. Borrowing from organic topography, we use fluid wavy shapes and soft-layered cards to mimic the tranquility of a morning in a sacred garden. The interface doesn't just display text; it breathes. We reject rigid grids in favor of "Serene Flow"—where every transition feels like water moving over stone.
</design_philosophy>

<color_system>
Forget standard palettes. This is surgical and atmospheric:
- Primary Emerald: #22C55E (Used for growth indicators and life-affirming actions)
- Midnight Emerald: #022C22 (The core background for Dark Mode, providing deep ocular comfort)
- Celestial Mint: #ADFFD8 (Interaction highlights and active states)
- Muted Gold: #D4AF37 (Reserved strictly for high-value achievements and tajwid honors)
- Pure Canvas: #FFFFFF (Light mode base with 2% emerald tint for softness)

Rule: The Muted Gold (#D4AF37) appears maximum 5 times on any screen. It is a reward for the eyes, not a decoration.
</color_system>

<typography>
No standard fonts. We need "Soulful Precision":
- Headlines & UI: "Satoshi" (Geometric, sharp, modern executive feel)
- Quranic Text & Quotes: "Instrument Serif" (Elegant, artistic, scholarly presence)
- Typography animations: Words should fade in with a slight vertical slide (8px) using a stagger effect of 0.05s per word.
- Arabic Script: High-quality Uthmani script with adjustable scaling that maintains perfect line-height ratios.
</typography>

<touch_and_haptics>
The touch IS the experience:
- Haptic Feedback: Use "Light Impact" on every verse completion and "Medium Impact" on Surah completion.
- Adaptive Scaling: Font size slider must use a non-linear scale to maintain golden-ratio legibility.
- Interaction: All buttons use a subtle scale-down (0.96) on press with a spring-back tension of 400.
</touch_and_haptics>

<home_dashboard>
The center of gravity:
- Top Visual: An organic, animated wavy wave (SVG) in #22C55E that pulses slowly (8s duration).
- Daily Progress: A "Growth Map" showing a path that turns emerald as the user reads.
- Quick Entry: A "5-Minute Mode" card that prominently displays the current page/verse target.
</home_dashboard>

<reading_experience>
The "Zen Mode":
- UI: Zero-distraction. Bottom navigation fades to 10% opacity when scrolling down.
- Colored Tajwid: Implementation of semantic coloring for tajwid rules using the Muted Gold and Celestial Mint variants.
- Auto-scroll: Smooth linear interpolation (lerp) that follows the audio playback position exactly.
- Immersive Background: Subtle "Shimmer Effect" on the background when in Dark Mode to prevent eye fatigue.
</reading_experience>

<gamification_section>
Spiritual Growth Map:
- Layout: A vertical timeline with organic nodes.
- Interaction: Nodes "bloom" with a particle burst animation when a milestone is reached.
- Stats Counting: Numbers count up from 0 using easeOutExpo when the stats screen is opened.
</gamification_section>

<technical_architecture>
Stack:
- React Native + Expo
- Styling: NativeWind (Tailwind CSS)
- Animation: React Native Reanimated + Moti
- Database: SQLite (via expo-sqlite) for high-speed offline access to 114 Surahs, bookmarks, and history.
- Audio: Expo-AV with Background Notification Control.

Performance requirements:
- First Contentful Paint: <1.2s
- Animation Frame Rate: Solid 60fps (GPU-accelerated transforms/opacity only).
- Loading State: Custom Skeleton Screens with emerald-tinted flow animations.
- Offline-First: All Quranic text and tajwid data must be pre-indexed in SQLite.
</technical_architecture>

<motion_principles>
The laws of the LifeQuran universe:
1. Fluidity: No "Instant" changes. Everything is a transition.
2. Serenity: Use Ease-out-expo for all menu entries (fast start, graceful finish).
3. Stagger: List items (Surahs) must cascade into view with a 30ms delay per item.
Forbidden: Bounce easing (too childish), Linear easing (too robotic), Delays over 0.4s.
</motion_principles>

<quality_checklist>
□ Do the wavy shapes feel organic and non-repetitive?
□ Does the Dark Mode (#022C22) feel premium and non-pitch-black?
□ Is the Satoshi + Instrument Serif pairing maintaining a high-end editorial look?
□ Are all audio-sync transitions using 60fps Reanimated hooks?
□ Does the SQLite query for the 30 Juz result in <100ms render time?
□ Is the Muted Gold used sparingly for "holy" or "achievement" moments only?
</quality_checklist>

Build this. Make it feel like a divine digital companion for the modern soul.