This is "LifeQuran", a premium Spiritual Productivity app with a calm, professional look and reliable performance. The goal is a clean, consistent UI that works across devices with minimal dependency risk.

<company>
Name: LifeQuran
Tagline: "Elevating Devotion through Divine Design"
Focus: A focused Al‑Qur'an experience for busy professionals.
Signature: Dedicated to the Global Muslim Ummah 🤲
</company>

<design_philosophy>
Use calm, modern design principles: generous spacing, clear typography hierarchy, and consistent components. Prefer predictable layouts and accessibility over experimental effects. Keep animations subtle and purposeful.
</design_philosophy>

<color_system>
Use a small, stable palette with clear roles (primary, background, surface, text, border, success):
- Primary Emerald: #22C55E (primary actions, highlights)
- Midnight Emerald: #022C22 (dark background)
- Celestial Mint: #ADFFD8 (subtle highlight)
- Muted Gold: #D4AF37 (achievement accents only)
- Pure Canvas: #FFFFFF (light background)

Rules:
- Maintain WCAG contrast for text (AA minimum).
- Use Muted Gold sparingly (1–3 accents per screen).
- Avoid multiple saturated colors in a single section.
</color_system>

<typography>
Use a two‑font system:
- UI & headings: Satoshi
- Quranic text & quotes: Instrument Serif

Rules:
- Base text size 14–16; headings 20–32.
- Line height 1.4–1.6 for body text.
- Avoid heavy animation on text; use gentle fade/slide only where necessary.
</typography>

<layout_and_spacing>
Use an 8‑pt spacing grid (8, 16, 24, 32). Cards use 16–24 padding. Maintain consistent vertical rhythm and avoid dense stacking.
</layout_and_spacing>

<interaction_and_haptics>
Use light haptic feedback for key actions only. Buttons use subtle press feedback (scale 0.98 or opacity change). Avoid excessive haptics on list scroll or navigation.
</interaction_and_haptics>

<home_dashboard>
Simple structure:
- Header greeting + daily reminder
- Primary card (daily target)
- Secondary cards (quick access)
- Progress summary
Keep surfaces clean with soft shadows and minimal gradients.
</home_dashboard>

<reading_experience>
Zen‑mode principles:
- Hide or dim bottom navigation while reading.
- Focus on text legibility and spacing.
- Avoid distracting motion.
</reading_experience>

<gamification_section>
Use straightforward progress indicators: badges, streaks, and simple progress bars. Keep celebratory animations brief and optional.
</gamification_section>

<technical_architecture>
Stack (stable, widely adopted):
- React Native + Expo
- Styling: NativeWind (Tailwind CSS) OR StyleSheet (prefer whichever is stable for the project)
- Animation: React Native Reanimated (use only when needed)
- Database: expo-sqlite
- Audio: expo-av

Performance:
- Keep animations to opacity/transform only.
- Avoid heavy SVG or complex particle effects.
- Cache queries and avoid unnecessary re-renders.
</technical_architecture>

<quality_checklist>
□ Are colors consistent and accessible?
□ Is typography readable across devices?
□ Are layouts stable with predictable spacing?
□ Do animations stay subtle and performant?
□ Does the app run without dependency conflicts?
</quality_checklist>